Guide to the Kennell A. Jackson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kennell A. Jackson papers
1968-2000
SC0802
Jackson, Kennell A., 1941-2005.
26.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Access Terms
African Americans --History --Study and teaching (Higher).; African Americans --Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-360
  - Unframed pastel portrait of K. Jackson (signed but illegible) (Box 1)
  - Framed note on napkin written at University Fellows meeting, 1985 May 7 (Box 2)
  - Framed photo of swimmers (Branner students?), inscribed and signed by same on reverse (Box 2)
  - Framed poster for undergraduate scholars program (circa 1988), clipping of Kennall Jackson's letter to campus report, and holograph note on launching of the program, Circa 1988, undated (Box MC)
  - Set of 4 photos of Branner students (male) and one postcard in one frame; postcard text is "Beware of These Boys" (Box MC)
- Professional papers, Accession-ARCH-2006-017
  - Source material, notes, correspondence, photographs, mostly African research, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
  - Course outlines, typescript of Jackson's book on Africa, notebook on African research, correspondence files, source materials, and photograph of Lindblom., 1970s (Box 2)
  - Files releated to Jackson's book "America is Me" and two audio tapes from KQED, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Course files (syllabi, lectures, exams, etc.), 1990s (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous sources on Africa and other topics (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Computer disks (Box 3)
  - Students' papers (Box 4)
  - Research notebooks 1968 and undated, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Book of origins No. 1, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Book of origins No. 2, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Book of origins No. 3, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Origins and Migration: the Kitui Evidence, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Customs: Kitui, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Customs: Njania (?), circumcision, etc., 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Famines, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Famines [the 11th book], 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Questions on famines, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Essay on famines, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Notes on trade, 1968, undated (Box 5)
    - Trade book 2, 1968, undated (Box 5)
  - Research notebooks 1968 and undated:, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Kilungu Utui research, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Utui research in Kitui, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Mbau book – Nwang'a, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Genealogical narratives and names, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Names vol. II, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Athiani and Athani Kitui, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Archives: first reading, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Preview book 1, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Second preview book, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled: notes on birds and other topics, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled (missing back cover): notes on names?, 1968, undated (Box 6)
    - Untitled: notes on proverbs and riddles, 1968, undated (Box 6)
  - Research notebooks 1968 and undated:, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Vol. 1, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - 3rd volume, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Vol. 4, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Vol. 5, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Vol. 6, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - Vol. 9, 1968, undated (Box 7)
    - 9 unlabeled volumes from African research, 1968, undated (Box 7)
  - Information from interviews with Africans, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Hair
    - Publications, clippings, etc. on African American hair (Box 8-14)
  - Oversize roll: several African maps, some are copies from the British Museum [in map case storage]
  - Framed original artwork, unsigned (Box 1os)
- Additional papers, Accession-ARCH-2006-127
  - Syllabi, lecture notes, and other class files (Box 2)
  - Western Culture Debate paper and other CIV files (Box 2)
  - Hambone (published by Cmte for Black Performing Arts) Vol. 1 Spring 1974, 1974 Spring (Box 2)
  - Slides of Africa and African life for class use (Box 2)
  - 2 review articles by KJ (Box 2)
  - Hand-drawn maps from African research (Box 2)
  - Outlines and drafts of his writings (Box 2)
  - Some correspondence (Box 2)
  - "10 Keys to Mentoring: The Undergraduate Scholars Program Experience," by KJ (Box 2)
  - Assorted articles and works by others (Box 2)
  - 2 microfilms (Box 2)
  - Class files (Box 3)
  - CIV materials (Box 3)
  - Student papers (Box 3)
  - Course readings/readers (Box 3)
  - Source materials and research files on his research in Africa, Black culture, and Black hair (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with John Huie, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Other correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 5)
  - Sources for his class on Toni Morrison (Box 5)
  - Paper and 1 reprint by KJ (Box 5)
  - Paper by Bruce Thompson "History and Anthropology after Marx" (Box 5)
  - Hand drawn map: Macro-Population Movements and Settlements in 19th Century Ukambani (1 original and 1 copy) (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1971, 1995-2000 (Box 7)
  - Assorted notes, 2000, undated (Box 7)
  - Biographical and bibliographical information (Box 7)
  - Conference papers by Kwesi Yankah and Karin Barber, 1989, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Course materials and one student paper, 1997-2000, undated (Box 7)
  - Sources on black hair and beauty (Box 7)
  - Hate mail (Box 7)
  - Assorted files from KJ’s African research, 1970s (Box 7)
- Additional papers, Accession-ARCH-2013-073
  - Student papers/newspaper clippings/miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student binder, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History 46S Coursereader, Winter quarter 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Senior Honors Thesis: "Paul Robeson on Africa: A Different Perspective on International Relations" Phyllis Elaine Simon, June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student papers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William Leo Hansberry, "Africa: The World's Richest Continent", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles Wesley, "W.E. DuBois: The Historian", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Readings on black women in academia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Research, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Readings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Research, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "A History of Reggae Music in the Bay Area 1972-1983" John Nordell, June 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Durkheimian Anthropology and Social Criticism in France 1885-1925" Bruce Thompson, 28230 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mau-Mau Syllabus, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History of East Africa Coursereader, Fall 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Chester Crocker and the Negotiations for Namibian Independence: The Role of the Individual in Recent American Foreign Policy" Amy Biehl, May 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Introduction to African History, Fall 1991/1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History 148: Intro to African History, Spring 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Political Change in Tropical Africa coursereader, Spring 1990/1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - History of East Africa Coursereader, Fall 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - History 249/349: Africa Since 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Introduction to African History coursereader, Fall 1991/1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Journal from a class?, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kenya Visit, Kennell A. Jackson, Jr., June-October 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Journal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)